ANDUALEM A. MEKONEN

Mobile: 202-903-8930 Email: mekonenandu@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Web Developer with a passion for web application development and experience in development projects using Scrum, Agile. Skilled in conceptualizing, designing, development, and deploying software containing logical and mathematical solutions to business problems. Dedicated to driving innovation with the ability to follow industry and technological trends, and facilitating early adoption of innovations

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Analysis, Design, Development, Documentation, Testing,
 Deployment, and production support
- Experience in working with Scrum/agile software lifecycle methodologies.
- Proficient understanding of HTML5, CSS3, server-side CSS pre-processing platforms, such as LESS and SASS
- Good understanding of advanced JavaScript libraries and framework such as React.js
- Experience in using React JS components, using concept of virtual Dom, create SPA, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, plus Redux
- Good understanding of asynchronous request handling APIs, RESTful Web Services using AJAX, JSON
- Good knowledge of debugging JavaScript and HTML code with Firefox Firebug and Google chrome JavaScript debugger.
- Used GitHub for source code management and for version control.
- Experience with Nods.js, PHP, Linux, Apache Server, server administration, and hardware experience
- Experience with Oracle 11g, SQL, PI/SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and Fairbase

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer | MTM Consulting Group | Arlington, VA January 2018– Present

- Collaborated with senior-level developers to develop projects for website throughout project lifecycle.
- Worked in Agile development environment using advanced Scrum methodologies.
- Involved designing in web pages using HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, React.js, Redux, Firebase, Nods.js, Mongo DB.
- Implemented stable React components and stand-alone functions to be added to any future pages
- Involved in writing application level code to interact with APIs, RESTful Web Services using AJAX, JSON.
- Worked with Jest framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code.
- Maintained existing code and functionality during assimilation into ongoing operations.

Web Developer | Concepts IT Inc. | Vienna, VA September 2017 – January 2018

- Worked on an Agile (Scrum) Development Team to deliver regular updates to team and project managers.
- Responsible for front-end UI design using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iQuery
- Worked on Cross-Browser compatibility and fixed the bugs for several browsers.
- Used Jira as the bug tracking system to track and maintain the history of bugs/issues.

Media Technician | Megabit Media LLC | Alexandria, VA September 2014 – January 2017

- Working knowledge of all types of basic consumer and professional video and audio equipment
- Perform hardware/software upgrades
- Assist in the deployment of our media systems and web interfaces, connectivity, backup, archive, and restore functions for those systems
- Provide "first-response" technical support and assistance to all relevant departments

EDUCATION

Northern Virginia Community College

- ASS in Information Systems Technology, 2019
- Certifications:

Web Design and Development Career Studies 2018
Database Specialist Career Studies 2018

ICI University

Bachelor of Art in Theology, 2004